A Guide to the Garnett Family Papers, 1789-1846
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Garnett Family Papers, 1789-1846
Library of Virginia
28488
87 leaves, photocopies.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by Dr. Charles Ryland, Warsaw, Virginia, 4 November 1974.
Biographical/Historical Information
Reuben Meriwether Garnett (1777-1847), served as a company captain in the 9th Virginia militia and sheriff of King and Queen County, Virginia. He married (1) Nancy Pendleton (b. 1791) on 23 December 1812 and (2) Lucy Ann Hutchinson (1806-1835) on 21 April 1829.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1789-1846, of the Garnett Family, primarily Reuben M. Garnett (1777-1847), of King and Queen County, Virginia. Consisting of accounts, contracts, chancery decrees, deeds, estate records, plats, receipts, and wills, the collection largely relates to land transactions and estate settlements. Also, includes documents concerning the sale and purchase of slaves.
Organization
Organized into the following three series: A. Deeds Relating to King and Queen County, Virginia, 1827-1842; B. Papers Relating to King and Queen County, Virginia, 1829-1846; C. Papers Relating to the Garnett Family, 1789-1821.
Contents List
- Deeds Relating to King and Queen County, Virginia, 1827-1842 (Folder 1)
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Edward and Mary Upshaw to Reuben M. Garnett, 19 September 1827, 4 p. (Folder 1)
  - Thomas White and wife to George D. Gatewood, 21 March 1828, 4 p.
  - Edward Wright to Reuben M. Garnett, 18 August 1828, 2 p. (Folder 1)
  - Joseph and Elizabeth Skelton to Reuben M. Garnett, 26 November 1829, 4 p. (Folder 1)
  - Thomas and Rosa Cook to Mary Garnett, 1 December 1829, 4 p. (Folder 1)
  - Edmund Lyne, Carter B. Fogg, and Richardson Lumpkin, 5 January 1830, 4 p. (Folder 1)
  - George and Lucy Gatewood to Reuben M. Garnett, 19 January 1830, 4 p. (Folder 1)
  - Edmund Lyne and Carter B. Flagg to Reuben M. Garnett, 21 May 1831, 3 p. (Folder 1)
  - John Watkin, executor of Philip Watkins, to Reuben M. Garnett, 19 January 1832, 3 p. (Folder 1)
  - Lucy Golden, administrator of Philip Golden, to Reuben M. Garnett, 11 February 1832, 4 p. (Folder 1)
  - Charles and Lucy Latham to Mary Garnett, 25 May 1832, 3 p. (Folder 1)
  - Garnett and Roxxy Greenstreet to Reuben M. Garnett, 15 February 1833, 3 p. (Folder 1)
  - James and Nancy Coleman to Reuben M. Garnett, 26 January 1836, 4 p. (Folder 1)
  - Robert Saunders to Reuben M. Garnett, 21 October 1837, 3 p. (Folder 1)
  - Richardson Lumpkin, executor of James Smither, to Reuben M. Garnett, 7 October 1839, 3 p. (Folder 1)
  - Joseph and Rosy Longest to Reuben M. Garnett, 10 March 1840, 3 p. (Folder 1)
  - Elijah and Kitty Schools to Reuben M. Garnett, 28 January 1842, 4 p. (Folder 1)
- Papers Relating to King and Queen County, Virginia, 1829-1846 (Folder 2)
  - Award of Referees and establishment of line between Susanna Eubank and Reuben M. Garnett, March 1834, 3 p. (Folder 2)
  - Edward Wright's allotment from the division of the lands of Lucinda E. Manthews and Sally Wright, n.d., 1 p. (Folder 2)
  - Amount of land belonging to Edward Wright, deceased, n.d., 1 p. (Folder 2)
  - Course of the land sold by William Hill to Henry Samuel, n.d., 1 p. (Folder 2)
  - Course of land sold by Richards to Hines, n.d., 1 p. (Folder 2)
  - Reuben M. Garnett. Account of attendance with processioners, February 1846, 2 p. (Folder 2)
  - B. S. Mathews. Memorandum to make a deed to R. M. Garnett (Folder 2)
  - James Roy Micows. Receipt to Reuben M. Garnett for slaves, 17 February 1840, 1 p. (Folder 2)
  - Value of Phebe Gresham's negroes and contract with R. M. Garnett for them, 23 September 1833, 3 p. (Folder 2)
  - Plat of "Roance" Land and Deed, 1 p., Ms (Folder 2)
  - Decree of King and Queen County Chancery Court regarding Barefoots vs. Pollard, 10 March 1829, 1 p. (Folder 2)
- Papers Relating to the Garnett Family, 1789-1821 (Folder 3)
  - Will of Ann Garnett, probated Essex County, 16 February 1789, 4 p. (Folder 3)
  - Account of Reuben Garnett, administrator of the estate of Mrs. Ann Garnett, 16 September 1799; copied 29 April 1805, 3 p. (Folder 3)
  - Inventory and appraisement of the estate of Ann Garnett, 10 April 1792, 2 p. (Folder 3)
  - Receipt by James M. Garnett, Jr., money amounting to the value of a black girl named Sally; bequeathed by Ann Garnett, 18 June 1821, 2 p. (Folder 3)
  - Receipt by R. Brooke, guardian of William G. Hunter, for part of Hunter's share from the estate of Mrs. Sarah Hunter, 9 April 1790, 1 p. (Folder 3)
  - Receipt signed R. Brooke, for fifty pounds, ten shillings, and six pence, from William Hunter's proportion of his mother's estate, 11 April 1792, 2 p. (Folder 3)
  - Receipt by James Hunter for seventy pounds, four shillings, and six pence, from Reuben Garnett, administrator of Sally Hunter, 18 March 1795, 2 p. (Folder 3)
  - Receipt by William G. Hunter for full satisfaction from Reuben Garnett as administrator, 30 April 1795, 2 p. (Folder 3)
  - Receipt by Jas. Hunter of money received from Reuben Garnett, administrator of Sarah Hunter, 3 August 1800, 1 p. (Folder 3)
  - Two receipts signed Jno. Stanard for sums received of Reuben Garnett following Fredericksburg Chancery Court executions, both dated 17 November 1818, 2 p. (Folder 3)
  - James Hunter's account for self, and as guardian, in account with Reuben Garnett, administrator of Sally Hunter and Ann Garnett, 1796, 1800, 2 p. (Folder 3)
  - Statement of account in M. G. Hunter's administrator vs. Garnett, as of 16 November 1818, by M. M. Marmaduke, 2 p. (Folder 3)
  - Statement of account, Richard Hackley in account with Muscoe Garnett, balance to 3 November 1795, 2 p. (Folder 3)
  - James Hunter's list of bonds received from Reuben Garnett, 8 January 1798, 1 p. (Folder 3)